Danny Boy is a drama, war, tv movie film directed by Sam Miller.
Soldier Brian Wood, is accused of war crimes in Iraq by
the human rights lawyer Phil Shiner.
The two men go head to head in a legal and moral conflict that takes us from the battlefield, at so-called Checkpoint
Danny Boy, to the courtroom and one of Britain’s biggest ever public inquiries, the Al-Sweady Inquiry.
Brian Wood, played by Anthony Boyle.
Phil Shiner, played by Toby Jones.
Lucy Wood, played by Leah McNamara.
Gavin Wood, played by Alex Ferns.
Patrick O'Connor, played by Tom Vaughan-Lawlor.
Stella Marshall, played by Sarah Niles.
Danny Boy is a 2021 British biographical drama
television film directed by Sam Miller.
It details parts of the life of war veteran Brian Wood.
The film tells the story of Brian Wood, a medal-winning war veteran who was accused of war crimes in Iraq during the Battle of
Danny Boy by the Iraq Historic Allegations Team, and follows his fight for the truth during the Al-Sweady Inquiry.
The film stars Anthony Boyle as Brian Wood, Toby Jones as human rights lawyer Phil Shiner,
Alex Ferns as Gavin, Brian's father, and Leah McNamara as Brian's wife.
Danny Boy  was first broadcast on BBC Two on 12 May 2021.
The tone is emotional.